Guide to the Jack Anderson papers, 1930-2004 MS2001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Merry-Go-Round columns, 1934-2004; 1948-2004; MS2001 Series 1; 79.5 Linear Feet 159 document boxes
  - Typescripts, Undated
    - Typescript [2/2], 1988 February (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 February (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Typescript [1/2], 1988 March (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Typescript [2/2], 1988 March (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 March (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Typescript [1/2], 1988 April (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Typescript [2/2], 1988 April (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 April (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 May (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 May (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 May (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 May (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 June (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 June (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 June (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 June (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 July (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 July (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 July (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 July (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Transcript [1/3], 1988 August (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Transcript [2/3], 1988 August (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Transcript [3/3], 1988 August (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 August (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 September (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 September (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 September (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 September (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 October (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 October (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 October (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 October (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 November (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 November (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 November (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 November (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Typescript [1/3], 1988 December (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Typescript [2/3], 1988 December (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Typescript [3/3], 1988 December (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1988 December (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1989 January (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 January (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 1989 February (Box 140, Folder 12)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 February (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 1989 March (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 March (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1989 April (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 April (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 1989 May (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 May (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, 1989 June (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 June (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1989 July (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 July (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 1989 August (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 August (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1989 September (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 September (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 1989 October (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 October (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, 1989 November (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 November (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1989 December (Box 142, Folder 10)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1989 December (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 1990 January (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 January (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 January (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1990 February (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 February (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 February (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1990 March (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 March (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 March (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1990 April (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 April (Box 143, Folder 11)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 April (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Typescript, 1990 May (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 May (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 May (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1990 June (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 June (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 June (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1990 July (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 July (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 July (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1990 August (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 August (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 August (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Typescript, 1990 September (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 September (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 September (Box 144, Folder 15)
    - Typescript, 1990 October (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 October (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 October (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1990 November (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 November (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 November (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1990 December (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1990 December (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1990 December (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1991 January (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 January (Box 145, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 1991 February (Box 145, Folder 12)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 February (Box 145, Folder 13)
    - Typescript, 1991 March (Box 145, Folder 14)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 March (Box 145, Folder 15)
    - Typescript, 1991 April (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 April (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Typescript, 1991 May (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 May (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, 1991 June (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 June (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1991 July (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 July (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, 1991 August (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 August (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Typescript, 1991 September (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1991 September (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 September (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1991 October (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Typescript for indexing, 1991 October (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 October (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1991 November (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 November (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, 1991 December (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1991 December (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - Typescript, 1992 (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - Typescript [2 of 2], 1992 (Box 430, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 1993 (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Typescript [2 of 2], 1993 (Box 430, Folder 2)
    - Draft typescript, 1994 (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - Typescript, 1994 (Box 430, Folder 3)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1994 (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - Typescript, 1995 (Box 147, Folder 15)
    - Typescript [2 of 2], 1995 (Box 430, Folder 4)
    - Camera-ready copy, 1996 (Box 147, Folder 16)
    - Typescript, 1997 January (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 1997 February (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Typescript, 1997 March (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1997 April (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, 1997 May (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 1997 June (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1997 July (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, 1997 August (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, 1997 September (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 1997 October (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - Typescript, 1997 November (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 1997 December (Box 148, Folder 12)
    - Typescript, 1998 January (Box 148, Folder 13)
    - Typescript, 1998 February (Box 148, Folder 14)
    - Typescript, 1998 March (Box 148, Folder 15)
    - Typescript, 1998 April (Box 148, Folder 16)
    - Typescript, 1998 May (Box 148, Folder 17)
    - Typescript, 1998 June (Box 148, Folder 18)
    - Typescript, 1998 July (Box 148, Folder 19)
    - Typescript, 1998 August (Box 148, Folder 20)
    - Typescript, 1998 September (Box 148, Folder 21)
    - Typescript, 1998 October (Box 148, Folder 22)
    - Typescript, 1998 November (Box 148, Folder 23)
    - Typescript, 1998 December (Box 148, Folder 24)
    - Typescript, 1999 January (Box 148, Folder 25)
    - Typescript, 1999 February (Box 148, Folder 26)
    - Typescript, 1999 March (Box 148, Folder 27)
    - Typescript, 1999 April (Box 148, Folder 28)
    - Typescript, 1999 May (Box 148, Folder 29)
    - Typescript, 1999 June (Box 148, Folder 30)
    - Typescript, 1999 July (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 1999 August (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Typescript, 1999 September (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 1999 October (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, 1999 November (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 1999 December (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 1999 (Box 430, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 2000 January (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, 2000 February (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, 2000 March (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 2000 April (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Typescript, 2000 May (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 2000 June (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Typescript, 2000 July (Box 149, Folder 13)
    - Typescript, 2000 August (Box 149, Folder 14)
    - Typescript, 2000 September (Box 149, Folder 15)
    - Typescript, 2000 October (Box 149, Folder 16)
    - Typescript, 2000 November (Box 149, Folder 17)
    - Typescript, 2000 December (Box 149, Folder 18)
    - Typescript, 2001 January (Box 149, Folder 19)
    - Typescript, 2001 February (Box 149, Folder 20)
    - Typescript, 2001 March (Box 149, Folder 21)
    - Typescript, 2001 April (Box 149, Folder 22)
    - Typescript, 2001 May (Box 149, Folder 23)
    - Typescript, 2001 June (Box 149, Folder 24)
    - Typescript, 2001 July (Box 149, Folder 25)
    - Typescript, 2001 August (Box 149, Folder 26)
    - Typescript, 2001 September (Box 149, Folder 27)
    - Typescript, 2001 October (Box 149, Folder 28)
    - Typescript, 2002 January (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, 2002 February (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Typescript, 2002 March (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Typescript, 2002 April (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, 2002 May (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Typescript, 2002 June (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 2002 July (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, 2002 August (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, 2002 September (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Typescript, 2002 October (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Typescript, 2002 November (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 2002 December (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Typescript, 2002-2003 (Box 430, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, 2003 January (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Typescript, 2003 February (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - Typescript, 2003 March (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - Typescript, 2003 April (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Typescript, 2003 May (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Typescript, 2003 June (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - Typescript, 2003 July (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - Typescript, 2003 August (Box 150, Folder 20)
    - Typescript, 2003 September (Box 150, Folder 21)
    - Typescript, 2003 October (Box 150, Folder 22)
    - Typescript, 2003 November (Box 150, Folder 23)
    - Typescript, 2003 December (Box 150, Folder 24)
    - Typescript, 2004 January (Box 150, Folder 25)
    - Typescript, 2004 February (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - Typescript, 2004 March (Box 150, Folder 27)
    - Typescript, 2004 April (Box 150, Folder 28)
    - Typescript, 2004 May (Box 150, Folder 29)
    - Typescript, 2004 June (Box 150, Folder 30)
    - Typescript, 2004 July; 76 Linear Feet 152 document boxes (Box 150, Folder 31)
    - Assorted typescripts, 1950-1959; Series 1 subseries 1 (Box 428, Folder 1)
    - Assorted typescripts, 1960-1969; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 428, Folder 2)
    - Assorted typescripts [1 of 2], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 428, Folder 3)
    - Assorted typescripts [2 of 2], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 428, Folder 4)
    - Korea columns, undated (Box 430, Folder 7)
    - Terrorism columns, undated (Box 430, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 150, Folder 32)
  - Article drafts, Undated
    - Article drafts, 1950-1959; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 228, Folder 1)
    - Article drafts [1 of 2], 1960-1969; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 228, Folder 2)
    - Article drafts [2 of 2], 1960-1969; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 228, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts [1 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 228, Folder 5)
    - Article drafts [2 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 228, Folder 6)
    - Article drafts [3 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 425, Folder 1)
    - Article drafts [4 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 425, Folder 2)
    - Article drafts [5 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 425, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts [6 of 6], 1970-1979; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 425, Folder 4)
    - Article drafts [1 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 229, Folder 1)
    - Article drafts [2 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 229, Folder 2)
    - Article drafts [3 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 229, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts [4 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 229, Folder 4)
    - Article drafts [5 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 229, Folder 5)
    - Article drafts [6 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 1)
    - Article drafts [7 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 2)
    - Article drafts [8 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts [9 of 9], 1980-1989; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 4)
    - Article drafts [1 of 4], 1990-2004; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 230, Folder 1)
    - Article drafts [2 of 4], 1990-2004; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 230, Folder 2)
    - Article drafts [3 of 4], 1990-2004; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 5)
    - Article drafts [4 of 4], 1990-2004; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 426, Folder 6)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [1 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 441, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [2 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 441, Folder 4)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [3 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 441, Folder 5)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [4 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 445, Folder 3)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [5 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 445, Folder 4)
    - Article drafts -- unlabeled [6 of 6], undated; Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 445, Folder 5)
- Index cards, 1933-1996; MS2001 Series 2; 26.5 Linear Feet 53 index card boxes
  Arranged alphabetically.
  First kept by Drew Pearson and then painstakingly maintained by Anderson's staff, this series contains index cards that capture the names of each person, place, or thing that was the subject of a Merry-Go-Round column from 1933 to 1996. Each entry briefly summarizes the column and notes the date that the column was published. The index cards are an invaluable tool for searching Merry-Go-Round columns (Series 1) and are also very interesting on their own as documentation of the extraordinary breadth and depth of the Merry-Go-Round columns. They are arranged alphabetically. This series also includes a small "TV Index" summarizing the topics of Anderson's television broadcasts in the 1970s and 1980s (presumably on Good Morning America), and well as a small "Index of Columnists" listing which columns were prepared by each of Anderson's many staff reporters.
  - A - America (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 154)
  - American - Army (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 155)
  - Army - Barron's (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 156)
  - Barrowclough - Blinn (Index Cards, undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 157)
  - Bliss - Brownell, H. (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 158)
  - Brownell, S. - Capital (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 159)
  - Capitol - Chiang (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 160)
  - Chicago - Commentators (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 161)
  - Commerce - Council (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 162)
  - Counter - Defense (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 163)
  - Defiance - Donnelly (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 164)
  - Donner - Eisenhauer (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 165)
  - Eisenhower - Farmer (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 166)
  - Farmers - Foggy (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 167)
  - Foglietta - Foreign Diplomats, Great Britain (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 168)
  - Foreign Diplomats, Kenya - Foreign Nations, Egypt (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 169)
  - Foreign Nations, Eire - Foreign Nations, Kuwait (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 170)
  - Foreign Nations, Labrador - Foreign Nations, Syria (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 171)
  - Foreign Nations, Tachen - Gasoline (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 172)
  - Gasque - Graham (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 173)
  - Grahl - Harker (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 174)
  - Harkin - Hnatio (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 175)
  - Hoax - Hubert (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 176)
  - Hubner - International (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 177)
  - Interoceanic - Jones (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 178)
  - Jonescu - Kerner (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 179)
  - Kerr - Laird (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 180)
  - Lait - Lindenbaum (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 181)
  - Linder - Maiden (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 182)
  - Mail - McCahey (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 183)
  - McCarthy - Merrow (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 184)
  - Merry-Go-Round - Moorhead (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 185)
  - Moose - National Commission (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 186)
  - National Committee - New York Times, undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 187)
  - New York University - Olin (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 188)
  - Oliphant - Pearson, Drew (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 189)
  - Pearson family - Post Office Dept. (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 190)
  - Postal Service - Rains (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 191)
  - Rainville - Ribicoff (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 192)
  - Ricardo - Roosevelt (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 193)
  - Root - Schneidermann (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 194)
  - Schneiders - Shearson (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 195)
  - Sheba - Soil (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 196)
  - Sok - Stevens (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 197)
  - Stevenson - Symington (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 198)
  - Symmes - Tilghman (Index Cards, undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 199)
  - Till - Union Tank (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 200)
  - Unions - Wagner (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 201)
  - Waite - Wenk (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 202)
  - Wenner - Wolfe (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 203)
  - Wolfenden - Z, misc. (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 204)
  - TV Index, A - N (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 205)
  - TV Index, O - V and Index of Columnists, A - Z (Index Cards), undated; MS2001 Series 2 (Box 206)
- Other Anderson publications, 1940-2005; MS2001 Series 3; 18.5 Linear Feet 33 document boxes, 2 flat boxes
  This series contains Anderson publications other than the Merry-Go-Round column, including magazine and newsletter articles (draft and final), book manuscripts, statements before Congress, and text and notes for speeches. The series also includes articles published about Anderson in magazines and newspapers, as well as drafts of Anderson biographies written by others. These materials date from 1940 to 2004. Anderson was the author or co-author of 17 booksboth nonfiction and fictionand was the Washington Bureau Chief of Parade magazine. The material in this series is arranged first by type of material (e.g. book manuscripts, published articles, and article drafts), and then alphabetically by publication title, and finally chronologically within each title.
  Book manuscripts include drafts of Anderson's nonfiction and fiction books (some of which were never published), as well as proposals and publicity materials for those books. These date from 1958 to 2005, and include the following titles: Alias Joey Cargo, Alice in Blunderland, America in Crisis, American GovernmentLike it Is, The Anderson File, Anderson Papers, The Ayatollah's Daughter, A Call to Action, Cambodia File, Case Against Congress, Confessions of a Muckraker, Congressmen for Sale, Control, Doomsday File, Fiasco, Good Ole Boys, Holy Mafia, How to Beat the System, I Was a Psychic Spy, Inside the NRA, The Japan Conspiracy, Kiss of Death, Kremlin, Making of a Muckraker, Millennium, The Muckrakers, Peace, War, and Politics, The Polygamists, The Saudi Connection, Stormin' Norman: An American Hero, USA: Second Class Power, Washington Expose, Washington Money-Go-Round, What's Wrong with America, Whistleblower's Manual, The White House Conspirators, and Zero Time.
  Published articles feature material written by Anderson for his newsletters Future File, Investigative Reporter, Jack Anderson Confidential, Personal from Pearson, and Washington Letter, as well as articles about Anderson published in newspapers and magazines. These date from 1940 to 2001. This series also includes several issues of Parade magazine containing Anderson's articles.
  Article drafts in this series include articles for Anderson's newsletters, Parade magazine, International Daily News, as well as statements before Congress and text and notes for speeches. Most are typed drafts with handwritten edits. These date from 1960 to 2004. Article drafts for the Merry-Go-Round column are contained in Series 1.
  This series has three subseries: Book manuscripts, Published articles, and Article drafts.
  Each of these subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - Book manuscripts, Undated
    - Alias Joey Cargo [Joe Valachi] [draft ch. 1-12], undated; Series 3 (Box 207, Folder 1)
    - Alias Joey Cargo [Joe Valachi] [draft ch. 13-33], undated; Series 3 (Box 207, Folder 2)
    - Alias Joey Cargo [Joe Valachi] [draft ch. 2-11], undated; Series 3 (Box 207, Folder 3)
    - Alias Joey Cargo [Joe Valachi] [draft chapters 9-33], undated; Series 3 (Box 207, Folder 4)
    - Alice in Blunderland [1 of 3], 1983; Series 3 (Box 207, Folder 5)
    - Alice in Blunderland [2 of 3], 1983; Series 3 (Box 208, Folder 1)
    - Alice in Blunderland [3 of 3], 1983; Series 3 (Box 208, Folder 2)
    - America in Crisis - outline, undated; Series 3 (Box 208, Folder 3)
    - America 1995: The Mega-Crises Converge, Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 444, Folder 2)
    - American Government...Like it is, undated; Series 3 (Box 208, Folder 4)
    - Anderson biography -- Chambless, Tim, undated; Series 3 (Box 208, Folder 5)